

PROFILE

Automation Test Engineer with 9+ years of experience. Developed and enhanced automation frameworks and scripts for cloud-based enterprise Web, Desktop, API applications using tools like Selenium, CodeceptJS, TestStack White, CodedUI, JMeter, Rest Assured with programming languages like Typescript, Python, Java, C# Dotnet, JavaScript.

OTHER TOOLS

AWS, Jenkins, JIRA, TestRail, GIT, NUnit, Junit, TestNG, SQL, Postman, Octopus Deploy, PyTest, Gherkin, Cucumber, Browser Stack, Lambda Test, Bitbucket, Linux, Windows, MacOS, Swagger

EDUCATION

Executive MBA, Finance and Operations NMIMS, A Grade, Feb 2017 to May 2019

B.Tech, Electronics & Computer Engineering SNIST, JNTU, 76%, Jun 2008 - May 2012

LANGUAGES

- English
- Hindi
- Telugu

RECOGNITIONS

- Super10 QA Innominds April 2019
- Pat On Back CDK November 2016
- Hackathon Winner CDK Oct 2015
- Star Award Infosy May 2015

ABHILASH SANNE ISTORY





PHONE: +91 9912085300 LINKEDIN: www.linkedin.com/in/sanneabhilash/ **EMAIL**: sanne.abhi@gmail.com **GITHUB**: sanneabhilash.aithub.io/sanneabhilash

Hacker Rank: hackerrank.com/sanneabhilash

KEY ROLES PLAYED

- Built Hybrid UI, API and Database integrated Automation Test Frameworks
- Reduce and optimize test execution time with custom execution strategies
- Built API based load test suite using JMeter to support upto 5X load
- Secured test data and configurations utilizing AWS S3, Secrets Manager
- Enhance test result reporting using Allure, Extent and custom inhouse reports
- CICD integration with customized Jenkins Jobs for automation tests
- Collaborated with CTOs for implementing test automation from scratch
- 3rd party integrations with TestRail, JIRA, BrowserStack, LambdaTest, HPALM
- Implemented dynamic test data creation and clean up strategies.
- Perform POCs to check automation compatibility with the product

AUTOMATION TOOLS

PlayWright, Selenium WebDriver, RestAssured, CodeceptJS, TestStack White, CodedUI, Appium, JMeter

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer in Test, Zenoti, Hyderabad

Dec2020-May2022

Part of Test Automation COE team. Maintained and Enhanced existing in-house keyword driven code less automation frameworks built with Python and dotnet. Worked with API, Web, Mobilte and Database Automation testing. Integrated Extent reports with inhouse custom frameworks for test results reporting.

Principal QA Automation Engineer, Innominds, Hyderabad Apr 2018-Dec 2020 Worked with start up projects as client for providing QA functional and automation testing solutions. Built and managed API regression automation suites with 99%+ execution efficiency. Streamlined Automation backlog and defect management in sprints.

Senior Test Automation Engineer, CDK Global, Hyderabad Jul 2015-Apr 2018 Build test automation framework for API and Desktop product testing using C# dotnet and Test Stack White. Migrated HP UFT based test scripts to C# dotnet automation framework. Regression Test Execution and results reporting.

Test Automation Engineer, Infosys Ltd, Hyderabad

Migration of CodedUI Test Automation scripts and framework to Selenium Webdriver. Test Execution, Failure Analysis and Results Reporting. Performing Automation feasibility analysis on functional tests.